<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>App Store Review Guidelines History</title><atom:link href="http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com</link><description></description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator><language>en</language><item><title>New rules for streaming game services and more</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2020-09-11-streaming-game-services-changes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2020-09-11-streaming-game-services-changes/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with changes to rules related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=xqk627qu&quot;&gt;streaming game services, hidden functionality in apps, and more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainly, Apple now allows for streaming game services as long as the included games can be downloaded directly from the App Store. Apple has also clarified that so-called “Reader apps”, like Netflix, can offer account creation for free tiers, and they’ve now made it more clear that having hidden, dormant or undocumented features in apps are not allowed, an obvious reference to the Fortnite situation.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete changes can be seen below:&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Push Notifications for marketing purposes, a 'Sign in with Apple' clarification and more</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2020-03-04-push-notifications-marketing-and-more/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2020-03-04-push-notifications-marketing-and-more/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with changes to rules related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=03042020a&quot;&gt;replies to reviews, spam, push notifications, &lt;em&gt;Sign in with Apple&lt;/em&gt;, data collection and storage, mobile device management, and more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, Apple now allows for marketing Push Notifications if the user has opted in to these and the guidelines related to &lt;em&gt;Sign in with Apple&lt;/em&gt; are now clearer, Apple having removed “exclusively”, which was used in a way that made it sound like you were only required to offer &lt;em&gt;Sign in with Apple&lt;/em&gt; if you exclusively used third-party login systems, which is not the case.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete changes can be seen below:&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Third-party analytics, ads in kids apps and 'Sign in with Apple'</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2019-09-14-kids-apps-ads-analytics-and-sign-in-with-apple/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2019-09-14-kids-apps-ads-analytics-and-sign-in-with-apple/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with changes to rules regarding &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=091202019a&quot;&gt;ads, data collection and privacy in kids apps&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=09122019b&quot;&gt;new rules about &lt;em&gt;Sign in with Apple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, it is now, in limited cases, permissible to show ads and include third-party analytics in kids apps and creators of kids apps must now comply with all applicable children’s privacy statutes. Newly submitted kids apps must follow these guidelines immediately, while existing apps will have until March 3, 2020 to be fully compliant. Regarding &lt;em&gt;Sign in with Apple&lt;/em&gt;, the guidelines now state that any apps that use a third-party login service, e.g. Facebook or Google, must also offer &lt;em&gt;Sign in with Apple&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete changes can be seen below:&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Restrictions to tracking of data in VPN apps and apps for kids, ban of HTML5 apps supporting digital commerce, and more</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2019-06-06-kids-privacy-no-gambling-vpn-changes-and-more/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2019-06-06-kids-privacy-no-gambling-vpn-changes-and-more/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with some significant changes, primarily focusing on rules surrounding data collection. Here’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=06032019j&quot;&gt;Apple’s own summary&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guidelines 1.3 and 5.1.4.&lt;/strong&gt; In order to help keep kids’ data private, apps in the kids category and apps intended for kids cannot include third-party advertising or analytics software and may not transmit data to third parties. This guideline is now enforced for new apps. Existing apps must follow this guideline by September 3, 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 4.7.&lt;/strong&gt; HTML5 games distributed in apps may not provide access to real money gaming, lotteries, or charitable donations, and may not support digital commerce. This functionality is only appropriate for code that’s embedded in the binary and can be reviewed by Apple. This guideline is now enforced for new apps. Existing apps must follow this guideline by September 3, 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 5.4.&lt;/strong&gt; Because VPN provides access to sensitive data, VPN apps may not sell, use, or disclose to third parties any data for any purpose, and must commit to this in their privacy policy. Certain types of apps — such as those for parental control, content blocking, and security — from approved providers may use the NEVPNManager API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 5.5. (New)&lt;/strong&gt; Because MDM provides access to sensitive data, MDM apps must request the mobile device management capability, and may only be offered by commercial enterprises, such as business organizations, educational institutions, or government agencies, and, in limited cases, companies utilizing MDM for parental controls. MDM apps may not sell, use, or disclose to third parties any data for any purpose, and must commit to this in their privacy policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 5.1.3(i).&lt;/strong&gt; Apps may use a user’s health or fitness data to provide a benefit directly to that user, such as a reduced insurance premium, if the app is submitted by the entity providing the benefit and the data is not shared with a third party. The developer must also disclose to the user the specific health data collected from the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 5.1.1(viii) (New).&lt;/strong&gt; Apps that compile information from any source that is not directly from the user or without the user’s explicit consent, even public databases, are not permitted on the App Store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 5.1.1(ii).&lt;/strong&gt; Apps must get consent for data collection, even if the data is considered anonymous at the time of or immediately following collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 1.1.3.&lt;/strong&gt; Apps may not facilitate purchase of ammunition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 4.2.7.&lt;/strong&gt; Remote desktop clients now include game consoles owned by the user. Software appearing in the client must be fully executed on the host device.
Demo videos of app functionality that is geo-locked or otherwise restricted are not accepted. Developers must provide a fully functional app for review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full changes can be seen below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Gifting in-app purchases</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2018-12-20-gifting-in-app-purchases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2018-12-20-gifting-in-app-purchases/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, adding some minor changes, the most important being a small change to now allow gifting in-app purchases:&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Changes after WWDC 2018</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2018-06-04-wwdc2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2018-06-04-wwdc2018/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;After the keynote of the World Wide Developers Conference 2018, Apple updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with a bunch of changes and new rules. It is clear that the theme of this update is user privacy and data protection. You can check out all the additions (marked with green) and removals (marked with red) below, but a few noteworthy changes include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps now must clearly describe new features and changes in the “What’s New” section of the App Store. Several of the large social network companies have been using a practice where they reuse a generic update text for every release and then enable new features remotely on a per-user basis. This appears to no longer be permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers are now allowed to provide time based free trials for non-subscription apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several new rules for apps dealing with cryptocurrencies. Apps are not allowed to mine coins, but in return cryptocurrencies no longer need to be “approved”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New rules for apps and games with advertising. Users now must be able to see all information used to target an ad without leaving the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New rules for apps that enable Remote Desktop access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emojis are back! Section 4.5.6 says that it is ok to use Unicode characters that render as Apple emojis inside apps and app metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All apps must include a link to their privacy policy in the App Store Connect metadata field and within the app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps must respect the user’s permission settings and not attempt to manipulate, trick, or force people to consent to unnecessary data access. For example, apps that include the ability to post photos to a social network must not also require microphone access before allowing the user to upload photos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps that enable sign in using a 3rd party social network must also include a mechanism to revoke social network credentials and disable data access between the app and social network from within the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a new Developer Code of Conduct section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out all the changes yourself below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Crypto currencies and ICOs, template apps, loot boxes and more</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-12-21-tba/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-12-21-tba/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Wednesday the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; was updated with quite a few changes. Besides some minor clarifications, new sections were introduced about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto currencies and ICOs now have a dedicated section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ban on template apps is clarified so its now more clear exactly what kinds of apps are affected. &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/20/apple-revises-its-controversial-guidelines-on-template-based-apps/&quot;&gt;Techcrunch spotted this change too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a few paragraphs on apps available for pre-order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details about what is allowed when offering so-called “loot boxes” in games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial apps must come from the financial institutions performing the services or they should at least use public APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new section on VPN apps details some rules specific to this app type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out all the changes below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>New guidelines for Face ID, ARKit, privacy policies and more.</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-09-15-face-id-arkit-privacy-policies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-09-15-face-id-arkit-privacy-policies/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;With the imminent release of iOS 11 and the announcement of the iPhone X with Face ID it was only natural for Apple to update the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. But this update is actually rather big and includes many changes that does not relate to the new products as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few notable changes and additions that caught my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t market your app with features or content it does not have (such as claimed “virus scanners”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must support in-app purchases initiated from the App Store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facial recognition for authentication must be implemented using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/localauthentication/&quot;&gt;official Apple API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps may facilitate peer-to-peer payments and are not required to use in-app purchases for such payments as long as no digital content or services are offered in exchange for rhe payment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Apps using ARKit should provide rich and integrated augmented reality experiences; merely dropping a model into an AR view or replaying animation is not enough.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section 4.7 changes some wording in the context of downloading and running 3rd party code from an app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list of app types that must include a privacy policy has been extended to also include “apps that utilize ARKit, Camera APIs, Photo APIs, or other software for depth of facial mapping information”. So if your app falls into this category make sure you have the privacy policy in place and save yourself for a rejection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data gathered from depth and/or facial mapping tools (e.g. ARKit, Camera APIs, or Photo APIs) may not be used for advertising or other use-based data mining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t visualize activity data in a way that resembles the Activity Rings in Activity control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAP renamed to in-app purchases everywhere (not all cases included in the diff below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some typos were fixed (not all included in the diff below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various other changes; Check the details below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description></item><item><title>New rules following WWDC 2017</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-06-08-new-rules-following-wwdc-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-06-08-new-rules-following-wwdc-2017/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;After a densely packed WWDC keynote with many new features for developers and user, Apple also published a new version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. There are many changes ranging from minor rephrasings to totally new rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few notable changes and additions that caught my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New note on how to respond to App Store customer reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note saying developers must now use the provided API to prompt users for reviews rather than link to the App Store page from a custom prompt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App names can now only be 30 characters long. Previosly this limit was 50 characters. There is a new subtitle feature in iTunes Connect that we should use instead of long descriptive titles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps that provide a programming interface may now (in some cases) download and run code from the Internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarifications regarding IAP and other purchasing methods for “reader” apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary options trading apps are no longer allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps created from a commercialized template or app generation service will be rejected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your app description should let people know what types of access (e.g. location, contacts, calendar, etc.) are requested by your app, and what aspects of the app won’t work if the user doesn’t grant permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the changes are listed below. Additions have green highlight and deletions have red highlight and strikeout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Added nonprofit payment exception</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-11-14-added-nonprofit-payment-exception/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-11-14-added-nonprofit-payment-exception/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;With this minor update to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; Apple added a subsection saying that approved nonprofits may fundraise directly within their app using Apple Pay. There is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/support/apple-pay-nonprofits/&quot;&gt;a link to a new page about how to become an approved nonprofit&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change followed an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/newsroom/2016/11/a-touch-of-giving-with-apple-pay.html&quot;&gt;official press release from Apple&lt;/a&gt; that details the new program allowing Apple Pay donations to nonprofits.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change also included Apple renaming Mac OS X to its new name macOS in several places.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Updated subscription rules, SiriKit, Stickers and more</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-09-01-subscriptions-siri-kit-stickers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-09-01-subscriptions-siri-kit-stickers/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;This update to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; is mostly about the new iOS features SiriKit and Stickers, but also includes the previously promised new rules for subscription based apps. The full diff is listed below, but a few interesting new bits include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;App names must be limited to 50 characters and should not include terms or descriptions that are not the name of the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was also mentioned in the “App Store Improvements” email sent to developers on September 1st and will be enforced for new apps and app updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 3.2.2 has a new point that I think is worth to notice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps should allow a user to get what they’ve paid for without performing additional tasks, such as posting on social media, uploading contacts, checking in to the app a certain number of times, etc. &lt;strong&gt;Apps should not force users to rate the app, review the app, download other apps, or take other similar actions in order to access functionality, content, or use of the app.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems to me that many apps and games currently encourage users to rate the app by offering rewards like free coins or similar for doing so. It will be interesting to see if Apple enforce this rule in a way that also prohibits this behavior where users are not forced, but gets rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember that even after your app has been approved, you should update your app to ensure it remains functional and engaging to new and existing customers. Apps that stop working or offer a degraded experience may be removed from the App Store at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes Apple will finally start to remove abandoned apps from the App Store. This should be a win for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Totally rewritten after WWDC keynote</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-06-13-totally-rewritten-wwdc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-06-13-totally-rewritten-wwdc/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;What a keynote! Apple announced significant updates for their 4 big platforms: iOS, macOS, watchOS, and tvOS. And right after the keynote ended the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; were also updated. But not just updated… Totally rewritten! The previous 30 sections have been reduce to only 5 sections but the word count has gone up from around 5000 words to over 6000 words.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will not include a diff showing what changed since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-04-19-carekit-apple-music&quot;&gt;the last update in April&lt;/a&gt; since basically &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; changed.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the introduction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guiding principle of the App Store is simple - we want to provide a safe experience for users to get apps and a great opportunity for all developers to be successful. We have updated the App Review Guidelines with that principle in mind. The guidelines themselves haven’t changed, but they are better organized and provide more context. On the following pages you will find guidelines arranged into five clear sections: Safety, Performance, Business, Design, and Legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week when &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2016/06/the_new_app_store&quot;&gt;Apple told journalists that App Store Subscription Pricing would no longer be limited to apps with media content and services&lt;/a&gt; there was &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2016/06/app_store_subscription_uncertainty&quot;&gt;much uncertainty to what that really meant&lt;/a&gt;. The new guidelines actually elaborates on that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auto-renewing subscriptions should only be offered using in-app purchase and may only be used for periodicals (e.g. newspapers, magazines), business apps (e.g. enterprise, productivity, professional creative, cloud storage), media apps (e.g. video, audio, voice, photo sharing), and other approved services (e.g. dating, dieting, weather)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I guess that means Apple have a whitelist of what kinds of apps will be allowed to use Subscription Pricing.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically you should read the new guidelines from start to end. If you stumble upon new rules that were not mentioned before, then please let us know so we can update this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>New Apple Music API section, CareKit and other updates</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-04-19-carekit-apple-music/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-04-19-carekit-apple-music/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Today Apple once again updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. It’s been 6 months since the last update, and the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/releasenotes/General/WhatsNewIniOS/Articles/iOS9_3.html&quot;&gt;iOS 9.3 release added several new developer APIs&lt;/a&gt;; so this update was not unexpected.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most significant is perhaps the new section 10.8 that states apps using background location services must provide a reason for doing so. What Apple considers a fair reason is not really clear although the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/MobileHIG/index.html&quot;&gt;HIG&lt;/a&gt; is mentioned.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another significant addition is the new section 30 about the Apple Music API that was introduced in iOS 9.3. As described in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/releasenotes/General/WhatsNewIniOS/Articles/iOS9_3.html&quot;&gt;iOS 9.3 release note&lt;/a&gt; the new API allows 3rd party apps to add music to a user’s Apple Music library and play it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The update did also include some minor additions mentioning new Apple products such as CareKit and Apple Music in various sections. Additions are highlighted in green below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Guidelines updated for tvOS apps</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-10-21-guidelines-updated-for-tvos-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-10-21-guidelines-updated-for-tvos-apps/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Along with other releases (iOS 9.1, watchOS 2.0.1 and tvOS GM) Apple silently updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; today. The changes listed below are mostly related to the release of the new Apple TV, but the new Apple Pencil also gets a mention.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new section 2.27 is rather confusing in its mention of the new Siri remote without explaining that the section only applies to tvOS apps (which we assume).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The updated section 3.6 now says that tvOS top shelf extensions must only show content that adhere to the 4+ age rating. This basically means that we should be very careful with using any user generated content for the top shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>After releasing iOS 9 Apple just renames Passbook and make no other changes</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-09-16-after-releasing-ios-9-apple-renames-passbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-09-16-after-releasing-ios-9-apple-renames-passbook/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of iOS 9 we expected Apple to make a bunch of changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-03-previews-flagging-privacy-policy-extensions-homekit-healtkit-testflight/&quot;&gt;they did last year&lt;/a&gt;. But this time the only change is that Passbook has been renamed to Wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Watch apps for telling time and Human Subject Research</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-04-28-watch-apps-for-telling-time-human-subject-research-ethics-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-04-28-watch-apps-for-telling-time-human-subject-research-ethics-review/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Shortly after customers begin to receive their Apple Watches and &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/04/27/apple-boasts-over-3500-apple-watch-apps-already-available/&quot;&gt;Apple boasts over 3,500 Watch apps are available&lt;/a&gt;, Apple made two small changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. The new section 10.7 states that watch apps must do more than just telling time. Also a new requirement on Human Subject Research says that the research should have approval from an independant ethics review board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Research Kit, Apple Pay recurring payments, SoundCloud downloads</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-03-12-research-kit-apple-pay-recurring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-03-12-research-kit-apple-pay-recurring/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;After the Spring Forward media event earlier this week Apple has updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with a few changes to the HealthKit so that it also mentions ResearchKit and there is a new paragraph on Apple Pay recurring payments. Finally there is a new paragraph stating that apps downloading media from online services such as YouTube, SoundCloud, and Vimeo etc. must obtain permission from those companies before doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Apple Pay Changes</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-11-apple-pay-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-11-apple-pay-changes/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Only a week after the last revision Apple again updates the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with a new section 29 on Apple Pay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Introducing Previews, Flagging, Privacy Policy, Extensions, HomeKit, Healtkit and TestFlight</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-03-previews-flagging-privacy-policy-extensions-homekit-healtkit-testflight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-03-previews-flagging-privacy-policy-extensions-homekit-healtkit-testflight/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Together with the iOS 8 release Apple updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with new sections on Extensions, HomeKit, HealtKit and Testflight. Some rules on the new app previews (videos) were also introduce along with a requirement to have a privacy policy and a flagging feature if the app has user generated content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Apple Allows Recommending Related Apps and Bitcoin Apps.</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-08-09-apple-allows-recommending-related-apps-and-bitcoin-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09  Aug 2014 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-08-09-apple-allows-recommending-related-apps-and-bitcoin-apps/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;Most notably in this set of changes of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, Apple now allows apps to show a collection of other apps that don’t have to be your own if they form a collection in a way Apple approves. Apps are now also allowed to facilitate transmission of approved virtual currencies. In other words Bitcoin apps are now officially allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>Cellular Download Limit and Kids Category</title><link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-03-30-cellular-download-limit-and-kids-category/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-03-30-cellular-download-limit-and-kids-category/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;A few general changes were introduced in this revision of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. The limit for downloading apps over 3G cellular were raised from 50 MB to 100 MB the iBookstore was renamed to iBooks Store. Section 24 “Kids Apps” was renamed to “Kids Category” along with the introduction of the new special App Store category.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item></channel></rss>