<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>App Store Review Guidelines History</title>
    <atom:link href="http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>New rules following WWDC 2017</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-06-08-new-rules-following-wwdc-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2017-06-08-new-rules-following-wwdc-2017/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a densely packed WWDC keynote with many new features for developers and user, Apple also published a  new version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. There many changes ranging from minor rephrasings to totally new rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few notable changes and additions that caught my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New note on how to respond to App Store customer reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note saying developers must now use the provided API to prompt users for reviews rather than link to the App Store page from a custom prompt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App names can now only be 30 characters long. Previosly this limit was 50 characters. There is a new subtitle feature in iTunes Connect that we should use instead of long descriptive titles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps that provide a programming interface may now (in some cases) download and run code from the Internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarifications regarding IAP and other purchasing methods for “reader” apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary options trading apps are no longer allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps created from a commercialized template or app generation service will be rejected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your app description should let people know what types of access (e.g. location, contacts, calendar, etc.) are requested by your app, and what aspects of the app won’t work if the user doesn’t grant permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Added nonprofit payment exception</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-11-14-added-nonprofit-payment-exception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-11-14-added-nonprofit-payment-exception/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With this minor update to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; Apple added a subsection saying that approved nonprofits may fundraise directly within their app using Apple Pay. There is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/support/apple-pay-nonprofits/&quot;&gt;a link to a new page about how to become an approved nonprofit&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change followed an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/newsroom/2016/11/a-touch-of-giving-with-apple-pay.html&quot;&gt;official press release from Apple&lt;/a&gt; that details the new program allowing Apple Pay donations to nonprofits.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change also included Apple renaming Mac OS X to its new name macOS in several places.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updated subscription rules, SiriKit, Stickers and more</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-09-01-subscriptions-siri-kit-stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-09-01-subscriptions-siri-kit-stickers/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This update to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; is mostly about the new iOS features SiriKit and Stickers, but also includes the previously promised new rules for subscription based apps. The full diff is listed below, but a few interesting new bits include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;App names must be limited to 50 characters and should not include terms or descriptions that are not the name of the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was also mentioned in the “App Store Improvements” email sent to developers on September 1st and will be enforced for new apps and app updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 3.2.2 has a new point that I think is worth to notice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps should allow a user to get what they’ve paid for without performing additional tasks, such as posting on social media, uploading contacts, checking in to the app a certain number of times, etc. &lt;strong&gt;Apps should not force users to rate the app, review the app, download other apps, or take other similar actions in order to access functionality, content, or use of the app.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems to me that many apps and games currently encourage users to rate the app by offering rewards like free coins or similar for doing so. It will be interesting to see if Apple enforce this rule in a way that also prohibits this behavior where users are not forced, but gets rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember that even after your app has been approved, you should update your app to ensure it remains functional and engaging to new and existing customers. Apps that stop working or offer a degraded experience may be removed from the App Store at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes Apple will finally start to remove abandoned apps from the App Store. This should be a win for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Totally rewritten after WWDC keynote</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-06-13-totally-rewritten-wwdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-06-13-totally-rewritten-wwdc/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a keynote! Apple announced significant updates for their 4 big platforms: iOS, macOS, watchOS, and tvOS. And right after the keynote ended the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; were also updated. But not just updated… Totally rewritten! The previous 30 sections have been reduce to only 5 sections but the word count has gone up from around 5000 words to over 6000 words.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will not include a diff showing what changed since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-04-19-carekit-apple-music&quot;&gt;the last update in April&lt;/a&gt; since basically &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; changed.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the introduction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guiding principle of the App Store is simple - we want to provide a safe experience for users to get apps and a great opportunity for all developers to be successful. We have updated the App Review Guidelines with that principle in mind. The guidelines themselves haven’t changed, but they are better organized and provide more context. On the following pages you will find guidelines arranged into five clear sections: Safety, Performance, Business, Design, and Legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week when &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2016/06/the_new_app_store&quot;&gt;Apple told journalists that App Store Subscription Pricing would no longer be limited to apps with media content and services&lt;/a&gt; there was &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2016/06/app_store_subscription_uncertainty&quot;&gt;much uncertainty to what that really meant&lt;/a&gt;. The new guidelines actually elaborates on that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auto-renewing subscriptions should only be offered using in-app purchase and may only be used for periodicals (e.g. newspapers, magazines), business apps (e.g. enterprise, productivity, professional creative, cloud storage), media apps (e.g. video, audio, voice, photo sharing), and other approved services (e.g. dating, dieting, weather)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I guess that means Apple have a whitelist of what kinds of apps will be allowed to use Subscription Pricing.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically you should read the new guidelines from start to end. If you stumble upon new rules that were not mentioned before, then please let us know so we can update this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Apple Music API section, CareKit and other updates</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-04-19-carekit-apple-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2016-04-19-carekit-apple-music/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today Apple once again updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. It’s been 6 months since the last update, and the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/releasenotes/General/WhatsNewIniOS/Articles/iOS9_3.html&quot;&gt;iOS 9.3 release added several new developer APIs&lt;/a&gt;; so this update was not unexpected.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most significant is perhaps the new section 10.8 that states apps using background location services must provide a reason for doing so. What Apple considers a fair reason is not really clear although the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/MobileHIG/index.html&quot;&gt;HIG&lt;/a&gt; is mentioned.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another significant addition is the new section 30 about the Apple Music API that was introduced in iOS 9.3. As described in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/releasenotes/General/WhatsNewIniOS/Articles/iOS9_3.html&quot;&gt;iOS 9.3 release note&lt;/a&gt; the new API allows 3rd party apps to add music to a user’s Apple Music library and play it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The update did also include some minor additions mentioning new Apple products such as CareKit and Apple Music in various sections. Additions are highlighted in green below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines updated for tvOS apps</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-10-21-guidelines-updated-for-tvos-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-10-21-guidelines-updated-for-tvos-apps/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Along with other releases (iOS 9.1, watchOS 2.0.1 and tvOS GM) Apple silently updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; today. The changes listed below are mostly related to the release of the new Apple TV, but the new Apple Pencil also gets a mention.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new section 2.27 is rather confusing in its mention of the new Siri remote without explaining that the section only applies to tvOS apps (which we assume).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The updated section 3.6 now says that tvOS top shelf extensions must only show content that adhere to the 4+ age rating. This basically means that we should be very careful with using any user generated content for the top shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After releasing iOS 9 Apple just renames Passbook and make no other changes</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-09-16-after-releasing-ios-9-apple-renames-passbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-09-16-after-releasing-ios-9-apple-renames-passbook/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of iOS 9 we expected Apple to make a bunch of changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-03-previews-flagging-privacy-policy-extensions-homekit-healtkit-testflight/&quot;&gt;they did last year&lt;/a&gt;. But this time the only change is that Passbook has been renamed to Wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch apps for telling time and Human Subject Research</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-04-28-watch-apps-for-telling-time-human-subject-research-ethics-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-04-28-watch-apps-for-telling-time-human-subject-research-ethics-review/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shortly after customers begin to receive their Apple Watches and &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/04/27/apple-boasts-over-3500-apple-watch-apps-already-available/&quot;&gt;Apple boasts over 3,500 Watch apps are available&lt;/a&gt;, Apple made two small changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. The new section 10.7 states that watch apps must do more than just telling time. Also a new requirement on Human Subject Research says that the research should have approval from an independant ethics review board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Kit, Apple Pay recurring payments, SoundCloud downloads</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-03-12-research-kit-apple-pay-recurring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2015-03-12-research-kit-apple-pay-recurring/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the Spring Forward media event earlier this week Apple has updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with a few changes to the HealthKit so that it also mentions ResearchKit and there is a new paragraph on Apple Pay recurring payments. Finally there is a new paragraph stating that apps downloading media from online services such as YouTube, SoundCloud, and Vimeo etc. must obtain permission from those companies before doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pay Changes</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-11-apple-pay-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-11-apple-pay-changes/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only a week after the last revision Apple again updates the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with a new section 29 on Apple Pay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Previews, Flagging, Privacy Policy, Extensions, HomeKit, Healtkit and TestFlight</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-03-previews-flagging-privacy-policy-extensions-homekit-healtkit-testflight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-09-03-previews-flagging-privacy-policy-extensions-homekit-healtkit-testflight/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with the iOS 8 release Apple updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; with new sections on Extensions, HomeKit, HealtKit and Testflight. Some rules on the new app previews (videos) were also introduce along with a requirement to have a privacy policy and a flagging feature if the app has user generated content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Allows Recommending Related Apps and Bitcoin Apps.</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-08-09-apple-allows-recommending-related-apps-and-bitcoin-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09  Aug 2014 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-08-09-apple-allows-recommending-related-apps-and-bitcoin-apps/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most notably in this set of changes of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, Apple now allows apps to show a collection of other apps that don’t have to be your own if they form a collection in a way Apple approves. Apps are now also allowed to facilitate transmission of approved virtual currencies. In other words Bitcoin apps are now officially allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cellular Download Limit and Kids Category</title>
      <link>http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-03-30-cellular-download-limit-and-kids-category/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://appstorereviewguidelineshistory.com/articles/2014-03-30-cellular-download-limit-and-kids-category/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few general changes were introduced in this revision of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;App Store Review Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. The limit for downloading apps over 3G cellular were raised from 50 MB to 100 MB the iBookstore was renamed to iBooks Store. Section 24 “Kids Apps” was renamed to “Kids Category” along with the introduction of the new special App Store category.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>